Finding Aid for the Anderson Samuel Weakley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Anderson Samuel Weakley Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0493
.1.68 linear_feet
- Correspondence - Outgoing. July 28,—1959- September 4, 1968. Outgoing correspondence of 3 letters. Letters are holograph, and are chronologically arranged by days and months. (Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Incoming. Incoming correspondence of 4 letters. Letters are holograph, and are alphabetically arranged. (Folder 1)
- Big South Road. Material includes 4 maps and 31 photographs of the Big South Road. Also included are approximately 200 pages of research notes. (Folder 1)
- Brown's Old Station. There are 2 maps, 2 photographs, and approximately 20 pages of research notes. (Folder 1)
- Fountain of Health. Material consists of 1 map, 3 photographs, and approximately 30 pages of research notes on the Fountain of Health. (Folder 1)
- Franklin Pike. Material includes 7 maps and approximately 100 pages of research notes. (Folder 1)
- Little South Road. There are 2 maps, 24 photographs, and approximately 200 pages of research notes. (Folder 1)
- Natchez Trace. Material consists of 5 maps, 1 photograph, and approximately 300 pages of research notes. (Folder 1)
- New Madrid Earthquake. Material includes 1 map, 16 photographs, and approximately 20 pages of research notes. (Folder 2)
- Old Chichasaw Trace. There are 9 maps, 20 photographs,- and approximately 250 pages of research notes. (Folder 2)
- Old McCutcheon Trace. Material includes 10 maps, 64 photographs, and approximately 250 pages of research notes. (Folder 2)
- Wartrace Creek. Material consists of approximately 30 pages of research notes. (Folder 3)
- Maps. Material includes 14 maps, 12 of which are U.S. Geological Survey maps. Each map contains miscellaneous notes and routes added by Samuel Anderson Weakley. (Folder 3)
- Research Notes. Material consists of approximately 30 pages of research notes on miscellaneous subjects. (Folder 3)
- Published Articles. Material includes 25 newspaper clippings of articles by Weakley published by The Nashville Tennessean and The Nashville Banner, dated from 1952- 1958. Also included are 10 issues of "The Lifeline", dated from 1941-1943, containing numerous articles by Samuel Anderson Weakley. (Folder 3)
- Published Articles About Samuel Anderson Weakley. There Are 5 clippings from The Nashville Tennessean, dated 1935-1957, about Samuel Anderson Weakley. (Folder 4)
- Newspapers; Newspaper and Magazine Clippings. Mater€ilj/L includes 2 centennial editions of The Nashville Banner and The Nashville Tennessean, dated Nov. 14, 1964 and Dec. 6, 1964. Also included are 16 newspaper and magazine clippings on miscellaneous subjects. (Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous- Material consists of a pamphlet published by the American Society of Civil Engineers, containing an article by Charles Senour, titled New Project For Stabilizing And Deepening Lower Mississippi River? a reprint frcm the Denver Post, dated July 8, 1929; 9 photographs relating to an article about Martha Shipton written by Weakley. Also included are 21 charts relative to the stages and floods of the Cumberland River. (Folder 4)
- Location: M/3/7
- Lebanon Dirt Road. Material includes 1 map and an 11 page essay, containing photograph titled "A Pictorial Trip From Nashville Along The Pioneer Lebanon Dirt Road" by S.A. Weakley. (Folder 4)
- This is a name index of the correspondents of Samuel Anderson Weakley. The figure (or figures) in parentheses immediately following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection? the dates are for the time of the letters. The full name of the writer is given wnenever possible. The last number given refers to the box in which the correspondence may be found.
- Bachofer, J. P., (1), Oct. 23, 1952; 1 (Folder B)
- Farnum, Jessica L., (1), Sept. 23, 1935; 1 (Folder F)
- Smartt, John M., (1), Aug. 13, 1958; 1 (Folder S)
- Turner, Hill, (1), Mar. 15, 1957; 1 (Folder T)